Aryan Mike Binazir

aryanbinazir.dev | abinazir@gmail.com | Raleigh-Durham, NC | LinkedIn | Github

Profile

Software Engineer with experience in technologies such as Go, JavaScript, and AWS. Led development of core components for Triage, an open-source Kafka proxy addressing head-of-line blocking issues. U.S. Citizen.

Skills

Go | JavaScript (Node.js, Express.js, React.js, npm) | TypeScript | Ruby | Bash Scripting

Databases (SQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, MySQLMongoDB, Redis)

Testing (Unit Tests, Integration Tests, Regression Tests)

Cloud (AWS EC2, AWS ECR, AWS Fargate, AWS CDK, AWS S3, AWS DynamoDB, Digital Ocean Droplet, Heroku)

REST APIs | HTTP | gRPC | Systems Design | Docker | Linux | HTML/CSS | Git/Github | Ngrok

Nginx | Message Queues | Apache Kafka | Message Queues | Event-Driven Architectures | Microservices

CI/CD | Agile Methodologies | Infrastructure as Code (Terraform, CDK, CloudFormation) | Serverless

Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer (team-triage.github.io), Triage @

2022 - present

Triage is an open-source proxy for Apache Kafka that addresses head-of-line blocking from poison pill messages and non-uniform consumer latency. It enhances parallel consumption, allowing for an at least tenfold increase in consumer connections per Kafka partition for downstream consumer instances.

- Designed and built Triage using Go, gRPC, Amazon Web Services (AWS) Fargate, and AWS Elastic Container Service (ECS)
- Led development of Triage core components, leveraging Go, including Go Channels & Goroutines to utilize concurrency, enabling parallel consumption of messages for Kafka consumers
- Leveraged Go and its concurrency features to halve the estimated development time compared to singlethreaded languages
- Enabled multiple downstream consumer applications to connect to Triage by developing Triage thin client library in Go and a gRPC service, allowing for an at least 1000% increase in connections per Kafka partition
- Containerized Triage service with Docker, streamlining the process of deployment to an AWS ECS cluster
- Automated infrastructure deployment strategy using AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK)/CloudFormation
- Built Node.js CLI tool, written in JavaScript and available as an npm package to simplify configuration, deployment, and teardown of Triage in the cloud
- Implemented application logic and design components allowing for the storage of poison pill messages in a dead-letter store using AWS DynamoDB
- Collaborated with a remote team of four engineers across two time zones
- Authored technical case study showcasing Triage, available at team-triage.github.io/case-study ℰ

Software Engineer, Open-Source Projects

2020 – 2022

- Request-Djinn an HTTP webhook inspector built using Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Digital Ocean Droplet, Nginx, PM2 & Tailwind CSS
- Online Outlet an e-commerce application created using Node.js, Express.js, React.js, REST APIs
- Address Buddy a contact management application developed with Node.js, Express.js & PostgreSQL
- BookWorm a book-viewing application built using Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, JavaScript & ERB

Start-Up Experience & Real Estate Investments

2011 - 2020

- Performed investment due diligence supporting opportunities for a start-up private merchant bank connecting investors with energy and other asset opportunities in emerging markets in Africa
- Built a real estate portfolio with properties in both the United States and South Africa

Education

Education	
M.B.A, University of Pretoria/Gordon Institute of Business Science	2012
B.S. in Computer Science, University of the Witwatersrand	2009